SRI HARSHA CHILAKAPATI

Bengaluru, India · +91 9494607964

sriharshachilakapati@gmail.com · goharsha.com

A self-enthusiast developer who is interested in developing applications for platforms of interest such as Android, Web, Desktop and also iOS. Had experience in building real-time applications optimized for performance. I'm always interested in exploring tech.

EXPERIENCE

1ST OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, JUSPAY

As an SDE at Juspay, I have worked on Android SDKs, especially payment pages and internal frameworks. The following are a few of my achievements at Juspay.

- Optimized Gradle build pipeline to make builds faster by 65%.
- Created new SDK architecture for Hyper SDK 2.0, a flagship product of Juspay.
- Created Debugging Tools for Juspay's open-source cross platform UI framework.
- Wrote the SDK hot reload feature for iOS SDK.
- Owned and maintaining an internal SDK framework.

1ST JUNE **2018** – **30**TH SEPTEMBER **2019**

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, JUSPAY

As an associate SDE at Juspay, I have worked on a lot of products, especially payment pages and internal frameworks. The following are a few of my achievements at Juspay.

- Part of the payment page team and worked on payment pages for Ola Money, Cred and Big Basket.
- Took ownership of Payment Pages for Foodpanda and Bounce (Android & iOS).
- Helped merchants integrate the Android Payment Page SDK, and created the VIES merchant demo app (Android) at Juspay.
- Created the coding guidelines and standards for the PureScript language.

4TH DECEMBER 2017 - 31ST MAY 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN, JUSPAY

As an SDE intern at Juspay, I have had amazing hands-on experience from day 1, which gave me a very good learning experience. The following are a few of my achievements at Juspay as an intern.

- Worked in a team of 8 to rewrite the entire BHIM UPI application into PureScript language using our new Presto open-source framework.
- Part of the 4-person team and created the first payment page prototype for Goibibo.
- Worked on the Express Checkout payment page aggregator and wrote generic API routing mechanism in PureScript language.

• I was one of the contributors to Presto UI, an open-source cross-platform native rendering technology that powers Juspay.

3RD MAY 2017 – 9TH JUNE 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN, MIRACLE SOFTWARE SYSTEMS

At Miracle, I learned MEAN Stack and the Ionic application framework. I worked there in a team of 6 persons and created a help system for employees. The following are its features:

- We made a responsive UI with a mobile-first approach using Material Design.
- The priority of the ticket created will be automatically computed based on the keywords.
- Uses NLP APIs from IBM Watson to analyze the tone of the message.

9TH JUNE 2017 – 30TH NOVEMBER 2017

TEACHING ASSOCIATE, SVEC TECHNICAL CLUB

I'm the co-founder of Technical Club in our college and a teaching associate, where we used to teach modern technologies to our juniors after college hours. We taught the following courses to our juniors:

- Modelling the database in NoSQL with MongoDB and Mongoose JS.
- Backend development using Node JS and Express JS.
- Introduction to Modern OpenGL (using OpenGL 3.3 with Core Profile).

Apart from these, I was also a co-student and learned how to create chatbots using JavaScript and Api.Ai (Now Google DialogFlow).

EDUCATION

GRADUATED FEB 2021

ANDROID KOTLIN DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

Graduated from Android Kotlin Developer Nanodegree from Udacity. As part of the curriculum, I have made 5 applications using modern architectures like MVVM and MVI. You can see the credential at https://graduation.udacity.com/confirm/GKADJRF9

EXPECTING TO GRADUATE IN 2021

IOS DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

Pursuing iOS Developer Nanodegree from Udacity. As part of the curriculum, I have made 2 apps out of which, one is a Meme Maker. Current progress is 89% in watching all lectures and 40% in doing practical projects.

EXPECTING TO GRADUATE IN 2021

UX DESIGNER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

Pursuing UX Designer Nanodegree from Udacity, and learning how to build interfaces which totally make use of human centered design principles. Current progress is 50% in watching all lectures and 20% in doing practical projects.

2013 BATCH

B. TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SVEC

Pursuing B. Tech at Sri Vasavi Engineering College in Computer Science Engineering, with an aggregate of 64.19% in academics.

SKILLS

- Knows 30+ programming languages. I can learn any programming language with ease.
- Strong in Kotlin, Java, JavaScript and PureScript.
- Knows multiple languages. Can read & write in English, Devanagari, Telugu, Kannada and Tamil.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

I always love undertaking new projects and spend my free time working on them. Here they are:

1. SilenceEngine, 2D/3D GAME ENGINE

SilenceEngine is a 2D/3D Java game engine which I started writing in 2014 November 16th. Since then, this project matured and has now got 116 stars, 27 forks with 11 contributors on GitHub. Initially, it was available for desktop only, but I have been working on ports to it in the form of pluggable backends which are now available for desktop, HTML5 and also Android.

2. WEBGL4J, WEBGL BINDINGS FOR GWT

This is a WebGL binding to the Java language. It allows GWT (Google Web Toolkit) users to write client-side web applications in Java which take advantage of the WebGL graphics library. This is used in the HTML5 backend of SilenceEngine.

3. GWT-AL, OPENAL IMPLEMENTATION IN GWT

This is a project which implements OpenAL audio specification in HTML5 for GWT. OpenAL is a C specification for playing low-level sounds, with spatial properties, simply said as playing 3D sounds. The OpenAL calls made by the user are delegated to the Web Audio API, making the application to run on any browser, even on mobiles.

4. EASYJSON & EASYXML, JAVA PARSERS FOR JSON & XML

These are educational parsers that I wrote in my 4th semester in college, with the goal of being simple to use than current ones, and also should be as less in size as possible. EasyJSON takes 11KB in the JAR, and EasyXML is 13KB in the JAR. They are also cross-platform and GWT compliant.

5. SIMPLYCPP, A C++ BEGINNERS IDE

The Turbo C++ IDE that we used in our C and C++ lab is good but unfortunately required some hacks to get it running on Windows 7 and above. So, I made my own C and C++ IDE using wxWidgets GUI toolkit and the TDM fork of the GNU C/C++ compiler.